<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Learning &#8211; Shantanu Khond</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.shantanukhond.me/tag/learning/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.shantanukhond.me/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 14:11:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Learn Java</title>
		<link>https://www.shantanukhond.me/2023/01/15/learn-java/</link>
					<comments>https://www.shantanukhond.me/2023/01/15/learn-java/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[shantanukhond]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 14:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[HomePage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.shantanukhond.me/?p=63</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Learn Java The Learn Java course is a comprehensive introduction to the Java programming language. It is designed for beginners who have little or no programming experience, but it is also suitable for experienced programmers who want to learn Java. The course covers all the essential concepts of the Java<a class="moretag" href="https://www.shantanukhond.me/2023/01/15/learn-java/"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-large-font-size">Learn Java</p>



<p>The Learn Java course is a comprehensive introduction to the Java programming language. It is designed for beginners who have little or no programming experience, but it is also suitable for experienced programmers who want to learn Java. The course covers all the essential concepts of the Java language and its standard libraries, from the basics of variables and data types to more advanced topics such as object-oriented programming, exception handling, and file input/output.</p>



<p>The course is divided into multiple videos, each covering a specific topic. The videos are well-structured, and easy to follow, and include examples, exercises, and quizzes to help you understand the concepts better. The course covers the following topics:</p>



<h2><a href="https://github.com/shantanukhond/LearnJava#appendix-for-learn-java-youtube-video-series"></a>Appendix for &#8220;Learn Java&#8221; YouTube video series:</h2>



<h3><a href="https://github.com/shantanukhond/LearnJava#learn-java-2-variables-and-literals-in-java"></a><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aX0DE1hVWMo&amp;t">Learn Java: 2 Variables and Literals in Java</a></h3>



<ul>
<li>This video provides an introduction to variables and literals in Java. It covers how to declare and initialize variables of different data types, including primitives and non-primitives, and how to use literals to assign values to them.</li>



<li>Additionally, the video also covers the scope of variables and how it is affected by different code blocks, and how to use type conversion and casting to convert variables from one type to another.</li>
</ul>



<h3><a href="https://github.com/shantanukhond/LearnJava#learn-java-3-strings-and-arrays-in-java"></a><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g2-i8s2dk-I&amp;t">Learn Java: 3 Strings and Arrays in Java</a></h3>



<ul>
<li>This video provides an introduction to strings and arrays in Java. It covers how to declare and initialize strings, as well as how to manipulate them using methods from the String class.</li>



<li>Additionally, the video also covers how to create, initialize, and manipulate arrays in Java, including how to use loops to iterate through arrays and how to use the Arrays class for sorting and searching.</li>
</ul>



<h3><a href="https://github.com/shantanukhond/LearnJava#learn-java-4-operators-in-java"></a><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g6Z-qmkMP18">Learn Java: 4 Operators in Java</a></h3>



<ul>
<li>This video covers different types of operators in Java including arithmetic, relational, logical, bitwise and assignment operators, and explains how to use them in various expressions.</li>



<li>Additionally, the video also covers the ternary operator and type comparison operator, as well as how to use the instanceof operator for determining the type of an object at runtime.<br><br></li>
</ul>



<p>At the end of the course, you will have a strong understanding of the Java programming language and be able to write your own Java programs. Additionally, you will also have the foundation to continue learning more advanced topics like concurrency and web development. This course is a great starting point for anyone who wants to become a Java developer or simply wants to learn to code.<br></p>



<p>Link to Series: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLH1gsHiD7JxhtWH9_HzGU1kZ6hPzn6ICD" target="_blank">Learn Java</a><br>Link to GitHub: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/shantanukhond/LearnJava" target="_blank">shantanukhond/LearnJava</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.shantanukhond.me/2023/01/15/learn-java/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
